this alkane kind of looks like an
octopus
the first step to naming is to find the
parent chain and number the parent
chains so the substituents are at the
lowest numbered position there's seven
carbons in the parent chain so the
ending of the name will be heptane next
means to find the substituents there's
one methyl here at position two and one
at position six and there's an ethyl
group at position four the ethyl comes
before methyl in the name because e
comes before m in the alphabet the final
name is four ethyl 2 6 dimethylheptane
thanks for watching don't forget to like
and also subscribe to the chemistry kit
for more